Guide to the Hermann Herrey papers, ca. 1939-1971.
Herrey, Hermann papers,
- Talks, Reports, etc. by H.H.
  - "Report about traffic and parking problems in connection with Rockaway Beach, Queens Co., N.Y." New York, Feb. 22, 1941, 2 (Box 13)
  - "About the Future of Our Big Cities" Address to American Academy of Arts and Sciences Nov. 10, 1943 a.) first draft b.) final c.) copy, 3 (Box 13)
  - "TVA's of the Future" Article for The American Scholar: article, data, and correspondence, June-Sept. 1945, 4 (Box 13)
  - "Program for Research on Community Centers" n.d., 5 (Box 13)
  - Book Report on The Planning Function in Urban Government by R.A. Walker, Cambridge, Dec. 10, 1942, 6 (Box 13)
  - "About the Scope of the Planning Function" Jan. 1943, 7 (Box 13)
  - "Intersecting Sheet Construction" New York, Jan. 1947, 8 (Box 13)
  - "Scenic Production Techniques in Television" New York, Jan. 1947, 9 (Box 13)
  - "Second Progress Report: A Center for Urban and Regional Studies" Feb. 18, 1953, 10 (Box 13)
  - "Report about a Scientific Approach Towards the Problems of Communication Planning" New York, Jan. 4, 1941, 11 (Box 13)
  - "Ionesco and 'Der Strom des Bewusstseins'", 12 (Box 13)
  - Followed by: 12 folders, 3 ring binders, 2 black notebooks, 1 gray notebook - these appear to be notes, drafts of chapters, etc., perhaps for a book (Box 13)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Reports and Talks - Drafts, Correspondence and Notes 1950s (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Reports and Talks - The American Scholar "TVAs of the Future" 1945 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Reports and Talks - "The Future of Our Cities draft October 1943 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Reports and Talks - "The Future of Our Cities draft October 1943 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Reports and Talks - "About Traffic and Parking Problems in Connection with Rockway Beach, Queens County, NY" 1941 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Reports and Talks - "Scenic Production Techniques in Television" 1954 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Reports and Talks - "The Crisis of Expansionism" (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Reports and Talks - Address to the City Club, New York Committee on Streets and Traffic 1941 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Reports and Talks - "The Period of Expansion Final Draft (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Reports and Talks - "About the Scope of The Planning Function", 1943 (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Reports and Talks - "Program for Research on Community Centers" (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Bound Report -"Intersecting Sheet Construction" Jan. 1947, NY (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Bound Report - "About a Scientific Approach Towards the Problems of Communication Planning", Jan. 4 1941, NY (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Notebook - Planning Notes (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Notebook - Planning Notes (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Notebook - I.R.D.A. (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Photographs (Box 14)
  - Portfolio - Hermann Herrey Architect, 1935-1935 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Designs, 1934-1934 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Designs, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Theater and set design, city planning, architectural projects, 1930-1930 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Theater and set design, city planning, architectural projects (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Theater and set design, city planning, architectural projects, 1930-1930 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Misc. photographs (Box 15 & 16 (o/s))
  - Prints and contacts of furniture and architecrural designs and Manhattan city planning., 1930-1953 (Box 15)
  - Designs (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Interior of Wohnung. Br Vollmer, Berlin (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Morgenthau House, Long Island (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Mactner House, Massapequa, Long Island (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Drawings chairs and houses (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of drawings in folder 4 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Misc. b/w prints interiors and exteriors (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Oversized drawings and plans (Box 17)
  - Album of b/w prints and drawings, Herrey's work, many missing from pages (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Plans for the store remodelling, 1952-1953 (Folder 1, Box 17)
  - Kant Garage, Berlin, plans for automatic self-service parking system (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Large photographs of a house (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Jacoby, Frankfurt (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Large Photographs of rooms and furniture (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
  - Wohnung Schaitzler (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Water, London, 1958-59 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Sketch of ? (Box 17, Folder 5, 7)
  - Wohnung Schatski (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Drawing of chair (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Chair and Furniture designs (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Drawing of Building (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Jacoby, Frankfurt (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Manhattan Interior Highway and Parking Belt (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Diploma of German Critics Award and sketch, 1958-1959 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Manhattan Interior Highway and Parking Belt (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Plans and Photgraph of proposed industrial facilities in NY (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Small Photographs of rooms and furniture (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Designs (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Nediks store (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Oversized drawings (possible set designs) (Box 18)
  - Houses designed by Hermann Herrey interiors (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Prometheus und Ephimetheus posters (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Houses designed by Hermann Herrey interiors (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - First Executed Stage Design, 1924 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Designs (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Large sketch of an auditorium (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Houses designed by Hermann Herrey interiors (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - City Painting (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Car (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Apocalyptic Scene Paintings (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
  - Chair (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Car (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - City Painting (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Theater set (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Figure Sketches (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Designs (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Patio Painting (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Theater set (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Painting Draft (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Misc. drawings traffic patterns (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Landscape/Architectural Painting Draft (Box 18, Folder 11-13)
  - Theaterpreis Diploma of German Critics Award (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Designs (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Designs (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Landscape/Architectural Sketch and Painting (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
  - Designs (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Designs (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Designs (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Landscape/Architectural Sketch (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Prometheus und Ephimetheus Carl Spitteler (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Architectural Painting Draft (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Prometheus symbol (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Possible Set Design Painting (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - P.u E. Carl Spitteler (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Landscape Painting (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - "First executed stage design of Hermann Herrey (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Room Sketch (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - City/Architectural Pastel Drawings (Box 18, Folder 22-29)
  - theater design (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - costume design (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Painting Labelled "Law" and "Court" (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Various Black and White Prints (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Landscape Painting (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - set design (Box 18, Folder 35)
- Miniature wooden model of a Jewish community center in Berlin-Charlottenburg, submitted in a competition (MU #1192) [original German title on box: "Wettbewerb fur den Neubau eines Gemeindehauses der Judischen Gemeinde zu Berlin in Berlin-Charlottenburg, Fasanaenstrasse 79-80"], 1 (Box 19)